Guide to the W.H. Cowley Papers SC0196
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal papers and writings, Series 1
  - Correspondence, writings and speeches, 1922-1978; Series 1B
    - Correspondence about WHC placement efforts for former students, Glogau, Arthur H. and Charles, Milton., 1964 Feb-1966 Dec (Box 42, Folder 65-17)
    - Correspondence about and copy of Grinager, Patricia dissertation proposal., 1965 Jan-Apr (Box 42, Folder 65-18)
    - Papers related to $50,000 grant from Stanford for WHC to hire research assistance. Williams, Donald T. appointed as research assistant., 1965 Jun-Oct (Box 42, Folder 65-19)
    - Outline and correspondence about WHC's speech at Cabrillo College., 1965 Jul-Sep (Box 42, Folder 65-20)
    - Correspondence and notes for WHC speech at the California Junior College Association., 1965 Aug-Nov (Box 42, Folder 65-21)
    - Correspondence about WHC speech for the American Nurses' Association which was cancelled because of WHC's illness., 1965 Jul-1966 May (Box 42, Folder 65-22)
    - Papers related to the College Entrance Examination Board Conference, Arizona. Cancelled by the CEEB., 1964 Sep and 1965 Aug (Box 42, Folder 65-23)
    - Correspondence regarding Stanford Today and Tomorrow Conference. Includes text of WHC speech and news clippings., 1965 Aug-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 65-24)
    - Papers about WHC consulting work for Wisconsin State University, Stevens Point., 1965 Aug-Dec (Box 43, Folder 65-25)
    - Correspondence with Duryea, Ed D., 1965 Aug-1966 Jan (Box 43, Folder 65-26)
    - Correspondence with Perdue, James E. about WHC consulting work for Oswego State College., 1965 Apr-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 65-27)
    - Correspondence about WHC consulting work for the Cortland State College with President Kenneth Young., 1965 Apr-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 65-28)
    - Correspondence with Zwingle, J.L. about WHC consulting work for the Association of Governing Boards., 1965 Aug-Oct (Box 43, Folder 65-29)
    - Correspondence and minutes from Hutchinson, Eric’s Advisory Committee meeting on his faculty master task., 1965 Oct-Dec (Box 43, Folder 65-30)
    - Professional notes accession sheets., 1965 (Box 43, Folder 65-31)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning 1965 version of an Overview of American Higher Education., 1965 Sep-1966 Mar (Box 43, Folder 65-32)
    - Student comments and grades, Overview of American Higher Education course., Fall 1965 (Box 43, Folder 65-33)
    - Correspondence with Hutchinson, Eric, about Weinberg article on the nature of scientific research., 1965 Aug (Box 43, Folder 65-34)
    - Correspondence and proposals about Gatchel, Richard's Freedom in American Higher Education study., 1965 Aug-1967 Dec (Box 43, Folder 65-35)
    - Correspondence about WHC’s academic government study for the Carnegie Corporation. See also 69-35., 1965 Dec-1966 Nov (Box 43, Folder 65-36)
    - Notes and outline for WHC's final presentation in the Administrative Staff Seminar, "Observations about Freedom in General." See also 65-13., 1965 Jun (Box 43, Folder 65-37)
    - Correspondence with Sanford, Nevitt about WHC's holism concept., 1965 Jul-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 65-38)
    - Correspondence about WHC's planned talk at Foothill College commencement, cancelled due to illness. See also 66-20., 1965 Dec-1966 Apr (Box 43, Folder 66-1)
    - Papers related to WHC’s National Association of Student Personnel Administrators talk and award, Seattle. See also 66-53., 1966 Jun-1967 Jan (Box 43, Folder 66-2)
    - Correspondence about WHC talk for the College Entrance Examination Board, San Diego., 1965 Dec-1966 Mar (Box 43, Folder 66-3)
    - Correspondence regarding WHC’s commencement address for the College of San Mateo, cancelled due to illness., 1966 Jan-Apr (Box 43, Folder 66-4)
    - Correspondence with the University of Michigan about invitation to teach summer session there. See also 64-46., 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box 43, Folder 66-5)
    - Papers relating to Wert, Robert J. move from Stanford Dean to professor in the School of Education., 1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-6)
    - "Student Unrest in Perspective," WHC article in the California Teachers Association Journal. Includes correspondence and rough drafts., 1966 Jan-Mar (Box 43, Folder 66-7)
    - Papers relating to IBM data processing course taken by WHC., 1965 Sep-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-8)
    - Correspondence relating to WHC's talk for the Stanford chapter of the AAUP., 1966 Jan-Mar (Box 43, Folder 66-9)
    - Correspondence regarding WHC talk to Merritt College., 1966 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-10)
    - Correspondence about Jones, Esther Lloyd guidance book manuscript., 1965 Oct-1966 May (Box 43, Folder 66-11)
    - Correspondence with Rowe, Jerry and Rawnsley, David about WHC's consulting work for San Mateo County., 1966 Mar-Jul (Box 43, Folder 66-12)
    - Correspondence and program brochure from the American Alumni Council-American Public Relations Association regional conference, San Francisco., 1965 Nov-1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-13)
    - Correspondence about WHC talk at Medsker, Leland L.’s seminar, University of California., 1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-14)
    - Papers relating to WHC's presentation for the International Center for the Advancement of Management Education, Stanford Graduate School of Business., 1966 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-15)
    - Correspondence about Tyler, Robert C.'s paper using WHC's taxonomy., 1966 Jan-1968 Oct (Box 43, Folder 66-16)
    - Papers related to WHC's consulting work for the California Teachers Association Commission on Higher Education., 1966 Feb (Box 43, Folder 66-17)
    - WHC review of Veysey, Lawrence R.'s The Emergence of the American University, Educational Forum. Page 35. Correspondence about., 1965 Nov-1966 Aug (Box 43, Folder 66-18)
    - Correspondence and newsletters from the G9.2 Society., 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box 43, Folder 66-19)
    - Correspondence about WHC's coronary thrombosis., 1966 Mar-Jul (Box 44, Folder 66-20)
    - Correspondence with Wise, Max of the Danforth Foundation., 1964 Nov-1966 Feb (Box 44, Folder 66-21)
    - "Analysis of the concept of Leadership," written for WHC seminar, Stanford, 6 pages., Winter 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-22)
    - "Values, Ideals, Aspiration," written for WHC seminar, 3 pages., Winter 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-23)
    - Correspondence inviting WHC to attend the Associated Students of Stanford University Asilomar Conference, on the role of the undergraduate and his education at Stanford., 1966 May-Jun (Box 44, Folder 66-24)
    - Correspondence about WHC’s Palomar College Talk. Does not include text of speech., 1966 Apr-Nov (Box 44, Folder 66-24A)
    - "What is Higher Education," introductory chapter from WHC manuscript "American Higher Education in Perspective.", Winter 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-25)
    - 8 versions of 66-25. (Box 44, Folder 66-25A)
    - "The Hellenic Fountainhead," chapter 1 from WHC manuscript "American Higher Education in Perspective.", Winter 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-26)
    - Correspondence with members of Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities About offer for WHC to head two year project to improve higher education in Brazil., 1966 Jun-Aug (Box 44, Folder 66-27)
    - Outline of WHC talk to Fellowship Forum on power in 1776., 1966 Jul (Box 44, Folder 66-28)
    - Correspondence regarding Long Island University offer of teaching position., 1966 1966 Jul-Sep (Box 44, Folder 66-29)
    - Papers related to WHC talk for the Kansas City Regional Council for Higher Education., 1966 Aug-Nov (Box 44, Folder 66-30)
    - Correspondence and papers related to WHC talk for the California Junior College Association, Fall Meeting, Chabot College., 1966 Nov-Dec (Box 44, Folder 66-31)
    - Papers related to Jacks, David Professor Search Committee., 1966 Oct-1967 Mar (Box 44, Folder 66-32)
    - Correspondence with Tuttle, William M. Jr., Conant, James B.’s biographer. See also 42-21, 42-25, 69-12 and 76-1., 1966 Jul-1968 May (Box 44, Folder 66-33)
    - Correspondence with Bersi, Robert M. about money owed WHC, and Bersi's efforts to interest Spillsbury, Duane in WHC's work., 1966 May-1968 Jun (Box 44, Folder 66-34)
    - Professional notes accession sheets., 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-35)
    - Correspondence with Burtness, Paul about his Phillips Foundation internship in academic administration., 1966 Jan-1967 Feb (Box 44, Folder 66-36)
    - Correspondence with Anderson, Florence of the Carnegie Corporation seeking financial support for WHC's research., 1966 Dec-1967 Jan (Box 44, Folder 66-37)
    - Correspondence with Bowles, Frank of the Ford Foundation., 1966 Dec-1967 Feb (Box 44, Folder 66-38)
    - Correspondence with Connolly, Bishop James L. of Fall River, MA about higher educational history., 1965 Dec-1966 Mar (Box 44, Folder 66-39)
    - Correspondence with Craig, William C. and Boyan, Norman, U.S. Office of Education, about financial support for WHC’s research., 1966 Aug-1968 Mar (Box 44, Folder 66-40)
    - Walker, Ronald W. weekly work reports., 1966 Jan-Oct (Box 44, Folder 66-41)
    - "The Hellenistic Age," chapter 2 of WHC manuscript. "American Higher Education in Perspective." MISSING (Second copy filed in PRP V.III, No. 43)., 1966 (Box 44, Folder 66-42)
    - Correspondence with Jordon, J.S. of John Wiley and Sons discussing publication of WHC's "A Holistic Overview of American Colleges and Universities.", 1966 Dec-1968 Jun (Box 44, Folder 66-43)
    - Correspondence with Chambers, M.M. about WHC's publication, The Grapevine, Chambers' book on the courts and the colleges, and WHC's manuscript, "Professors, Presidents and Trustees.”, 1965 Dec-1967 May (Box 44, Folder 66-44)
    - Correspondence with Zwingle, J.l. of the Association of Governing Boards., 1966 Jan-Dec (Box 44, Folder 66-45)
    - Letter of resignation from Risser, Betty, WHC's secretary., 1966 Aug 19 (Box 44, Folder 66-46)
    - Correspondence and notes from visit with Gideonse, Harry about WHC's "Student Unrest in Perspective," and HG's retirement plans., 1966 May-1967 Jan (Box 45, Folder 66-47)
    - Correspondence with Morrill, J.l. about WHC article, "Critical Decisions in American Higher Education.", 1966 Sep-Nov (Box 45, Folder 66-48)
    - "Private Philanthropy in Higher Education," excerpts from WHC writings printed in Stanford University News Service release., 1966 Feb 28 (Box 45, Folder 66-49)
    - Correspondence about Jacks, David Professorship search and Mayhew, Lewis B. involvement., 1966 Jan-1968 Feb (Box 45, Folder 66-50)
    - Papers related to the Hanna Committee on his proposed Higher Education Institute., 1966 Jan-Feb (Box 45, Folder 66-51)
    - Memo from Williams, Donald T. about his trip to set up a Stanford ERIC for higher educational administration., 1966 (Box 45, Folder 66-52)
    - Papers related to award from the National Association of Personnel Administrators, presented to WHC for distinguished service., 1966 Jun (Box 45, Folder 66-53)
    - Correspondence and newsletters from the G9.2 Society., 1967 (Box 45, Folder 67-1)
    - Correspondence and notes of speech for the American Friends Service Committee, Portland College., 1967 Jan-Apr (Box 45, Folder 67-2)
    - Papers related to Stanford School of Education Faculty Seminar., 1967 Feb 21 (Box 45, Folder 67-3)
    - Correspondence with Williams, Donald T. concerning suggestions for revision of Course 308., 1967 Feb-1968 Mar (Box 45, Folder 67-4)
    - Correspondence regarding WHC consulting work for the Stanford University Board of Trustees., 1966 Dec-1968 Jun (Box 45, Folder 67-5)
    - Correspondence and list of students from WHC's teaching at the University of Michigan Summer Session., 1966 Nov-1967 Oct (Box 45, Folder 67-6)
    - University of Michigan student rating forms., 1967 (Box 45, Folder 67-6A)
    - Correspondence and daily calendar from WHC's University of Lancaster Conference and visit to England, arranged by McGrath, Earl. Includes paper read at conference, "Academic Government in Britain and the United States.", 1966 Dec-1968 Jul (Box 45, Folder 67-7)
    - University of Lancaster, Grasmere Conference on the Purposes and Assessment of Methods in Higher Education: program, list of papers read, copies of papers by WHC and others., 1967 Apr (Box 45, Folder 67-7A)
    - Correspondence and outline of talk to Chico State College., 1967 Mar (Box 45, Folder 67-8)
    - Papers related to WHC’s Stanford University Public Affairs Fellowship Program talk., 1967 Feb-May (Box 45, Folder 67-9)
    - Papers related to two WHC talks given at Michigan State University., 1967 Feb-Aug (Box 45, Folder 67-10)
    - Manuscripts and outlines for 67-10 talks. (Box 45, Folder 67-10A)
    - Coladarci Committee to select a new Jacks, David Professor: log of daily developments, list of persons under consideration, correspondence., 1967-1968 Mar (Box 45, Folder 67-11)
    - Correspondence related to 67-11., 1967-1968 (Box 45, Folder 67-11A)
    - Correspondence with Cronbach, Lee and Silberman, Charles E. about WHC article, "The Need for Conceptually Oriented R~search in Education," and "The Academic Lazzaroni.", 1967 Feb-1969 Feb (Box 45, Folder 67-12)
    - Correspondence about distribution of copies of WHC manuscript, "An Overview of American Colleges and Universities.", 1966 Jan-1967 Mar (Box 45, Folder 67-13)
    - Correspondence with McGrath, Earl J. of Teachers College, Columbia University about Hefferlin, J.B.'s work there., 1962-1967 (Box 45, Folder 67-14)
    - Correspondence with Columbia University Oral History Project about WHC contribution to the Carnegie Corporation history., 1967 May-Sep (Box 45, Folder 67-15)
    - Correspondence with the University of Illinois Press about possible publication of WHC manuscript., 1967 Mar-Jun (Box 45, Folder 67-16)
    - Correspondence about WHC talk for the Stanford Alumni Association, Tucson, OK., 1967 May-Sep (Box 45, Folder 67-17)
    - Unanswered letters., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-18)
    - Analysis of WHC taxonomy by Hind, Robert R., Spring, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-19)
    - G9.2 Society biographical sketches. (Box 46, Folder 67-20)
    - Correspondence with Hubbard, Guy about WHC talk at the University of Indiana., 1967 Aug-Dec (Box 46, Folder 67-21)
    - Correspondence about WHC’s course 308, An Overview of American Higher Education, as taught at Michigan State University., 1967 Aug-Sep (Box 46, Folder 67-22)
    - Correspondence and related papers for WHC consulting work at Sacramento State College., 1967 Oct (Box 46, Folder 67-23)
    - Papers related to WHC critique of Hefferlin, J.B.’s manuscript, "The Dynamics of Academic Reform," for the Kettering Foundation Study., 1967 Oct-Dec (Box 46, Folder 67-24A)
    - Correspondence with Johnson, Franklin A. of the Donner Foundation about $25,000 grant to WHC. See also 67-26 and 69-4., 1967 Apr-1968 Nov (Box 46, Folder 67-25)
    - Correspondence with Gideonse, Harry, Chancellor of the Hew School of Social Research. See also 66-47 and 67-25., 1967 Jun-1969 Oct (Box 46, Folder 67-26)
    - WHC review of the California Oath Controversy, by Gardner, David P., The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, page 211., 1968 May (Box 46, Folder 67-27)
    - Correspondence with Pettit, Dean Joseph M., Stanford University School of Engineering about his engineering education report., 1967 Sep-Dec (Box 46, Folder 67-28)
    - Professional note accession sheets., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-29)
    - "The Concepts of Energy, Power, and Force," WHC paper written at the University of Michigan., 1967 Jul (Box 46, Folder 67-30)
    - "The Value Taxon," from WHC course 308., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-31)
    - "The Purpose Taxon, from WHC course 308., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-32)
    - "The Problems Taxon," from WHC course 308., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-33)
    - Papers related to WHC student, Funk, Robert: correspondence, dissertation proposal and biography., 1964-1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-34)
    - Papers related to Bacchetti, Raymond F.’s participation in the search for a new Jacks, David Professor., 1967 Oct-1968 Dec (Box 46, Folder 67-35)
    - "Time, the Temporal Continuity Taxon," course 308, Stanford., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 67-36)
    - Papers related to Wert, Robert J.’s acceptance of the Mills College Presidency. Includes correspondence about $50,000 grant RJW helped get for WHC's research., 1949-1969 (Box 46, Folder 67-37)
    - Papers related to WHC's three day lecture series at the University of Connecticut., 1967 Nov-1968 Dec (Box 46, Folder 68-1)
    - Correspondence about WHC consulting work for Haggerty, William J., 1968 Feb-May (Box 46, Folder 68-2)
    - Papers concerning Nurses' Seminar, Emory University. (Box 46, Folder 68-3)
    - Application for grant. (Box 46, Folder 68-3/1)
    - Correspondence., 1968 Feb-1969 Dec (Box 46, Folder 68-3/2)
    - Papers from first seminar week., 1968 Mar 4-8 (Box 47, Folder 68-3/3)
    - "Stipulated Definitions Employed in the C-H-W Holistic Taxonomy for the Study of Social Institutions," 3 pages., 1968 Feb 17 (Box 47, Folder 68-3/4)
    - Papers from second seminar week., 1968 (Box 47, Folder 68-3/5)
    - McLaughlin, Dean's and WHC’s taxonomic examples; also other related papers., 1968 Nov (Box 47, Folder 68-3/6)
    - "Summary of Stipulated Definitions in the Taxonomy," See also 68-3/4 and 68-6., 1968 Feb 17 and 1968 Oct 10 (Box 47, Folder 68-4)
    - Correspondence with Bond, Kendell H., University of Illinois about WHC speech given in 1940, "Fire Always Makes Room for Itself.", 1968 Feb-Jun (Box 47, Folder 68-5)
    - WHC proposal to William, Donald T. and Hefferlin, J.B. about working with him to develop taxonomy. See also 68-3/4 and 68-4., 1968 Feb-May (Box 47, Folder 68-6)
    - "Write it Right and Brightly," revision edited and reproduced by former student, Glyer, Richard. Includes correspondence., 1968 Feb-Jul (Box 47, Folder 68-7A)
  - Correspondence, writings and speeches, 1922-1978; Series 1C
    Miscellaneous correspondence and papers including Cowley's 'Kind Words and Criticism' series, 'Requests for Help' series, 'Former Students' series, and four volumes of the Daily Dartmouth.
    - Misc. correspondence
      - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with former students
      - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - A-G, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - H-R, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - S-Z, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1956-1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - J. B. Hefferlin, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Robert Johns, 1953-1964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Robert Johns, 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Robert Johns, 1954-1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Robert Johns, 1955-1969 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Andreas Psomas, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Donald T. Williams, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - D. T. Williams revision of WHC's course outline book ms., "An Overview of American Higher Education." See also Series I-D, folder 67-4., 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - D. T. Williams' data for Professors, Presidents and Trustees: Government and Education chapter. See also Series II-A, Box 14, F327.70. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - D. T. Williams' final revision of aProfessors, Presidents and Trustees (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - D. T. Williams' revisions of WHC's "A Short History of American Higher Education" ms, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Incoming correspondence: kind words and criticisms
      - 1938 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - 1939-40 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - 1941-42 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - 1942-46 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - 1946 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - 1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - 1948 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - 1950 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - 1951 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - 1953 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - 1956 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - 1958 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - 1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - 1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - 1961 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - 1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - 1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - 1964 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - 1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - 1966 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - 1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - 1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - 1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - 1973-74 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - 1975 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Incoming correspondence: unanswered letters
      - 1950 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - 1951 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Incoming correspondence: requests for WHC writings
      - 1965 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - 1966 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - 1968 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - 1969 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Incoming correspondence: requests for research help from WHC
      - 1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - 1961 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - 1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - 1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - 1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - 1967 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - 1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - 1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - 1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing correspondence: chronological files
      - 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - 1973 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - 1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)